Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ wolfgangfriedrich (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Air Freight
Logistics Management
Freight Forwarding

Languages

German (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

Wolfgang Friedrich

Logistics Consultant

United States

Summary

International Logistics/Transportation Manager with extensive business expertise in the USA, Europe and Asia.

More than 20 years experience in the Asia Pacific region with leading global

transportation companies in senior level positions (Malaysia, Taiwan, Hong Kong) and more than 10 years experience with international logistics companies in the USA.

Experienced in all aspects of managing international freight forwarding operations in a multi-cultural environment

Experience

Royal Cargo Inc., USA
Managing Director
December 2018 - April 2020 (1 year 5 months)
Los Angeles, California, United States

Royal Cargo Inc., Country Manager June 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 7 months) Taipei City, Taiwan

Establish Taiwan Branch Office, manage all activities of international transportation.

Self Employed Consultant - Transportation & Logistics Consultant

January 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 5 months)

Taiwan/Los Angeles, CA

NDO America, Inc.
Branch Manager
October 2013 - January 2015 (1 year 4 months)

Agility GIL

Branch Manager October 2011 - February 2013 (1 year 5 months)

Agent Liaison North America International Transportation Liaison for USA March 2009 - June 2011 (2 years 4 months)

Pro-Logistics Malaysia + USA
Managing Director
June 2004 - February 2009 (4 years 9 months)
Kuala Lumpur/Los Angeles

Gebr. Weiss GmbH

Development Manager Air/Sea East Europe
September 2001 - June 2004 (2 years 10 months)

Danzas Taiwan Ltd.

Managing Director

October 1996 - April 2001 (4 years 7 months)

Education

Business School Vienna Austria Business Administration